Tabbasum Bashir

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Highly qualified Science Teacher with 5 years of experience teaching middle and high school. Generates student enthusiasm for learning through individual connections and motivators. Empowers students through interactive learning, offering fun and educational lessons and exciting science demonstrations. Proactive and caring worker combined with communication strengths and good observational skills. Skillfully handles day-to-day activities while looking for opportunities to make a difference. Talented Tutor offering outstanding communication and problem-solving skills. Fosters positive learning environment by encouraging students to develop individual skills. Talented Tutor offering outstanding communication and problem-solving skills. Fosters positive learning environment by encouraging students to develop individual skills.

WORK HISTORY

SALSABEEL EDUCATIONAL INSTITUTE - High School Science Teacher

Srinagar

06/2019 - 04/2022

- Taught science courses using a lab-based learning model to deepen subject mastery.
- Understood critical development years for adolescent minds and structured lessons to meet cognitive abilities.
- Provided student academic support outside class time to improve learning and performance.
- Demonstrated willingness to accept feedback and make corrections based on advice from peers, parents and principal.
- Offered clear and constructive student discipline, discouraging inappropriate behavior and bullying.

LUCENT INTERNATIONAL SCHOOL - High School Science Teacher

Magam

03/2018 - 05/2019

- Inspired academic success based on belief that all students can achieve excellence, regardless of background.
- Selected and requisitioned appropriate books and instructional aids to complement lesson plans.
- Planned, prepared and taught lesson plans, giving students individual support.
- Taught science courses using lab-based learning model to deepen subject mastery.
- Communicated with students and parents regarding academic progress, assignments and behavior.
- Demonstrated positive and effective classroom management skills.

ISCC - Coaching Tutor

Srinagar

03/2021 - Current

- Led strategic discussion regarding training and coaching work plan.
- Assisted classroom training to promote hands-on practice and simulation to maximize learning.
- Developed working relationships with front-line leaders.
- Motivated students towards learning and studying to build self-confidence and reduce fear of failure.
- Supported students with helpful study habits and exam strategies.

LANGUAGES

English

Urdu

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

Bilingual or Proficient (C2)

Kashmiri

Advanced (C1)

Srinagar, India 190018 +91 9797031975 tabbasumbashir@gmail.com

SKILLS

- Records Maintenance
- Student Progress Analysis
- Course Materials Development
- Tutoring and Mentoring
- Classroom SupervisionBehavioral Skills
- Benavioral Skill
 Development
- Multitasking Abilities
- Problem-Solving
- Self-Motivated
- Flexible and Adaptable
- Excellent Communication
- Student Motivation and Engagement

EDUCATION

08/2014

Barkatullah University Bhopal,India

Master of Science: Botany

08/2014

CED College of EducationNarbal

Bachelor of Education

12/2012

Govt. College For Women Nawakadal

Srinagar

Bachelor of Science: Science Education

Government Girls Higher Secondary Nawakadal Srinagar

Higher Secondary Education

Skip to content